<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Translator's Notes</title><link>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/index.html</link>
<description>You should read them</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 21:43:50 -0300</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 21:43:50 -0300</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Translating an indie game: Satan's Pepper
</title><description><![CDATA[

<img src="./src/satans_pepper.png" alt="screenshot">
<p>
  I just translate a very cool indie game called <a href="https://theonlyghostwolf.itch.io/satans-pepper-portuguese">Satan's Pepper</a> by <a href="https://theonlyghostwolf.itch.io/">ghostwolf</a>. The game was made in a Jam contest in 5 days, as far as I know, and the outcome is pretty impressive. The author says he has plans for future versions of the game. Let's wait for it!
</p>
<p>This actual version is short, but you can have a lot of fun with your friends (or alone) if you like horror games and interactive games.</p>
<p>About the translation process, ghostwolf provides a manual, but I found it really easy. I spent last year learning code (Python and Javascript mainly), so it was  a bit intuitive for me what should and what should not be translated in the file. </p>
  <p>You can find a lot of Satan's Pepper gameplays on Youtube in a lot of different languages. Now we have a Portuguese translation, I'm waiting for the Brazilian gameplays!</p>











<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/translating-an-indie-game-satans-pepper.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=AlmirPaul0'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/translating-an-indie-game-satans-pepper.html'><span id='count-12429'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/translating-an-indie-game-satans-pepper.html</link>
<guid>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/./translating-an-indie-game-satans-pepper.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Almir Paulo</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 12:58:57 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Subtitles for Batman
</title><description><![CDATA[

<iframe width="100%" height="auto" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jDw2zag1K2Y" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>
  This weekend I worked in very a exciting project: Portuguese subtitles for a Batman film. Ok... Not really an official Batman film, it was a fan made film. But the story is great!
</p>

<p>
  It's called "Bats & Jokes", by Farbod Ardebili. As you can imagine by the title, there is the Joker in the story! Here is the synopsis:
  <blockquote>
Joker has broken out of Arkham Asylum and all the villains are now under his command. Two-Face, Penguin, Riddler, Deadshot, Killer Croc, they all take orders from Joker now! As usual, Batman is on his way to save Gotham once more, but nobody can expect what is about to come next. No one except for Darkseid maybe!
This is the story of Gotham's longest night filled with tales of death, immortality, apocalypse, destiny, and time travel! 
But most importantly this is the night that Joker's true origin and real name will be revealed to the world.
  </blockquote>
</p>

<p>
  I could practice my subtitling skills and I found an interesting software for subtitles. Actually I didn't need it in the end, but I will certainly use it in future occasions. 
</p>



























































<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/subtitles-for-batman.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=AlmirPaul0'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/subtitles-for-batman.html'><span id='count-4732'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/subtitles-for-batman.html</link>
<guid>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/./subtitles-for-batman.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Almir Paulo</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 23:09:57 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Contributing to Webtoon... Again.
</title><description><![CDATA[

<img src="./src/webtoon_translation2.png" alt="war-n-peas">
<center>
  Contributing to <a href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/challenge/war-and-peas/list?title_no=63305&page=1">War and Peas</a> by <a href="https://warandpeas.com/about/">Elizabeth + Jonathan</a>.  
</center>

<p>
  As I said the last time I worked with webtoons, it was a nice experience, and it was again. But I confess the last time <a href="https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/contributing--to-webtoons.html">with Dr. Frost</a> I may have made some mistakes. I realize that by look at other Portuguese translations that was better than mine in some aspects like visuals (in the font styles, that I notice that it's not really preserved as the originals, but reworked) and in the word choices at some points.</p>

<p>
  But now I've found another really interesting webtoon called "War and Peas". It's actually a kind of a comic strip. A very funny one. Here is the synopsis:
<blockquote>
A robot hopelessly in love, a promiscuous yet self-assured witch, and a fatally laid-back grim reaper. This never-ending webcomic of woefully funny stories will leave you cry-laughing or the other way around.
</blockquote>
</p>

<p>
I think I will continue to translate War and Peas from time to time. Translating comedy is a special challenge, it's not just changing the words (it's never that simple), you have to keep the meaning to keep the joke. An excellent practice for every translator.
</p>































<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/contributing-to-webtoon-again.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=AlmirPaul0'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/contributing-to-webtoon-again.html'><span id='count-19959'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/contributing-to-webtoon-again.html</link>
<guid>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/./contributing-to-webtoon-again.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Almir Paulo</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 15:08:09 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Contributing  to Webtoons
</title><description><![CDATA[

<img src="./src/webtoon_translation.png" alt="webtoon_translations">
<center>
Contributing to the translation of <a href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/mystery/dr-frost/list?title_no=371">Dr. Frost</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/jongbeom">JongBeom Lee
</a>
</center>


<p>
  I had a very nice experience these days translating a famous webtoon: Dr. Frost. The webtoons platform has support for fans translations. There is a huge community translating all sort of webtoons you can imagine. I thought it would be nice to try it once. And Dr. Frost is a webtoon that is helping me a lot to practice my french. I mean, of course the original tongue is probably Korean, but there is a french translation too.
</p>
<p>
  If you don't know what a webtoon is, it's a webcomic, actually webtoon is the name of a famous website where you can find a lot of them, but the name kind of sticks to the webcomics. And if you don't know Dr Frost here is a synopsis directly from Webtoons:
  <blockquote>College professor by day, and bartender by night, psychologist Dr. Frost believes in one simple belief. Humans are all the same. He uses this tenet to guide his practice, and solves the puzzles of the human mind one by one.</blockquote>
</p>

<p>
  I've said I am reading Dr. Frost in french, but this time, I translated with the pair english-portuguese. The episode in particular was one where Pavlov (Dr. Frost's dog) goes to play with other dogs, and then it comes out Pavlov knows a bit of Psychology too. haha.
</p>

<p>
  Some special details I’ve learned from translating a comic are an attention to the available space in the balloons (Sometimes you need to choose other words to fit them) and the font styles that need to be preserved for the sake of art. 
</p>

<p>
  Well, it was a very nice experience after all. I would like to do it again, but it would be better if I got paid. haha.
</p>

































<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/contributing--to-webtoons.html&text=&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;&via=AlmirPaul0'>Comments? Tweet</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/contributing--to-webtoons.html'><span id='count-1659'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/contributing--to-webtoons.html</link>
<guid>https://almirpaulo.github.io/blog/./contributing--to-webtoons.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Almir Paulo</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 19:00:34 -0300</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
